growmap.com 2019-12-11

# Privacy Policy

It is GrowMap’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating growmap.com.

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, GrowMap collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. GrowMap’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how GrowMap’s visitors use its website. From time to time, GrowMap may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

GrowMap also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. GrowMap does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

**Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to growmap.com choose to interact with GrowMap in ways that require GrowMap to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that GrowMap gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask commenters to provide a name, URL and email address. GrowMap collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with GrowMap. GrowMap does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Aggregated Statistics**

GrowMap may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to growmap.com. However, GrowMap does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

GrowMap discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on GrowMap’s behalf or to provide services available at growmap.com, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using growmap.com, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. GrowMap will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, GrowMap discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when GrowMap believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of GrowMap, third parties or the public at large. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. GrowMap takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. GrowMap uses cookies to help identify and track visitors, their usage of growmap.com, and their website access preferences. GrowMap visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using growmap.com, with the drawback that certain features of growmap.com may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, growmap.com may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in GrowMap’s sole discretion. GrowMap encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

###############

Thank you to [WordPress](https://automattic.com/privacy/) for making their Privacy Policy available to others. If you need one yourself, head on over and modify theirs. They’ve nicely made it available under a Creative Commons Sharealike license.

The following two tabs change content below.

  * Bio
  * Latest Posts

Gail Gardner is the founder of GrowMap.com. She is a Small Business Marketing Strategist who mentors small businesses, bloggers, and freelancers. After 23 years in the field with IBM and 5.5 years managing AdWords accounts, her focus shifted to small business marketing strategy. GrowMap.com is listed by Cision as a Top 100 Site for Marketers and has received three Small Business Influencer Awards from Small Business Trends. Named by D&B a Top 50 SMB Influencer on Twitter, you can follow Gail [@GrowMap](https://twitter.com/growmap) and on [LinkedIn](https://www.linkedin.com/in/growmap).
